# MATEUS FIORI, MSC

DATA SCIENTIST, SOFTWARE ENGINEER

• Avaré-SP - Brazil

**J** +55 (14) 9 8104-7858

in linkedin.com/in/mateusfiori

github.com/mateusfiori

Download PDF

#### Profile

Data Scientist with a Master's degree in Computational Intelligence by São Paulo State University (UNESP) with great interest and experience in topics such as NLP, Deep Learning, Machine Learning and Software Engineering as a whole. Highly organized and motivated by the countless challenges provided by the area.

#### Experience

### Finch Soluções

06/2020 - Current

#### **Data Scientist**

Planned, developed and maintained data science software services to enhance specific internal processes.

Developed natural language processing and machine/ deep learning models.

Exploratory data analysis.

Conducted tech courses for team members.

Investigated available resources to develop more useful project plans.

Completed reviews of codes, requirements and project plans.

Designed and developed scalable and optimized.

APIs using Python / FastAPI in order to turn the created models available to external usage.

### New Way Soluções Digitais

05/2019 - 06/2020

### **Software Engineer**

Squad leader.

Planned and developed microservices solution to integrate company's main solution.

Tasks planning and management.

### New Way Soluções Digitais

06/2018 - 05/2019

#### **Full Stack Web Developer**

Developed and maintained features for company's main solution.

Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.

Contributed ideas and suggestions in team meetings and delivered updates on deadlines, designs and enhancements.

### New Way Soluções Digitais

06/2018 - 05/2019

#### Mentor

Provided guidance on learning Python programming language.

Provided exercises and projects to improve learning.

#### New Way Soluções Digitais

03/2018 - 10/2018

#### **Data Classification Supervisor**

Managed 6 people team with the goal of classifying a large amount of natural language data.

Data corpus classified successfully.

Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.

#### **Data Classification Intern**

Data classification in general.

### Jr.com - Empresa Junior de Computação de Bauru

01/2016 - 03/2017

#### Vice President

Managed a group of student directors. Created company's legal documentation along with the President.

#### Skills

### AI Model Development System Engineering

Very well experienced on developing a wide variety of machine learning models to solve business problems.

## Communication and Proactivity

Oustanding team work ability having empathy and clear communication. Open minded and always open to learn something new.

Microservice engineering from planning to production, prioritizing organization and clean/intuitive code.

### Leadership

Comfortable and experienced on having a leading position. Proven ability to work with people. Great active listener.

### Agile

Proven ability and experienced on working in an agile (Scrum) team. Deep understanding of the scrum cerimonies.

#### Teaching and Learning

Curious and fast learner. Proven ability to teach and/or explain theoretical concepts about software engineering and artificial intelligence.

#### **Technical**

Python	Machine/Deep Learning	REST-RESTful
Docker	Natural Language Processing	Message Broker (RabbitMQ)
SQL / NoSQL	Linux	Software Design
GIT	Data Science	Data Visualization

#### **Education**

São Paulo State University - UNESP

Computer Science

São Paulo State University - UNESP

Master Degree - Computational Intelligence